一个关于评论的简短概括词。
A quick general word about commenting.
优秀的软件开发人员在代码中写评论，
Good software developers write comments in their code,
但他们做这件事谨慎而明智。
but they do it carefully and judiciously.
最好的评论是做我们关心的三件事
The best comments are ones that do the three things we care
大约在2005年，它们使代码更容易理解，
about in 005, they make the code easier to understand,
因为你已经写下来了
they make it safer from bugs, because you've written down
未来维护人员将拥有的重要假设
important assumptions that future maintainers will have
去关注，他们会让它更容易改变。
to pay attention to, and they make it more ready for change.
所以有一种至关重要的评论
So one crucial kind of comment that does all three
这些东西的规格说明。
of these things is a specification.
Spec出现在方法上方或类上方
Spec appears above the method or above a class
并记录该方法或类的行为。
and documents the behavior of that method or class.
在Java中，我们通常将其写成Java.comment，
In Java, we usually write it as a java.comment,
这意味着它以/**开头，通常包括字段
meaning that it starts with /** and typically includes fields
以@like@参数和@return开头。
that start with an @ like @parameter and @return.
这是一个函数规范的例子
So this is an example of a spec for a function
我们以前见过的。
that we've seen before.
规范的作用是记录假设。
What's specifications do is, they document assumptions.
我们已经提过几次了，
We've already mentioned them few times,
在以后的课上我们会有更多关于他们的话题，
and we'll have lot more to say about them in a future class,
但这是一种非常重要的评论。
but that's a super important kind of comment.
你应该在每种主要方法之前都看到这样一个
You should see one like this before each major method
在你的代码中分类。
and class in your code.
另一种非常重要的评论
Another really important kind of comment
如果你复制了一段代码
is one that says where a bit of code came from if you copied it
或者从其他地方改编。
or adapted it from somewhere else.
对于实践软件开发人员来说非常重要
Super important for practicing software developers
当你从网上复制代码时，我们做了很多。
when you copy code from the web, and we do a lot of that.
例如，我们发现
For example, we find examples of how
在堆栈溢出时执行操作并复制或调整它们
to do things on Stack Overflow and copy them or adapt them
我们的密码。
into our code.
每当我们这样做的时候，我们应该
And whenever we do that, we should always
有评论说这是从哪里来的。
have a comment that says where this came from.
一个理由是它能帮助我们
One reason to say that is that it helps us
避免侵犯版权。
avoid violations of copyright.
所以在堆栈溢出时这些小片段
So these kinds of small snippets on Stack Overflow
通常属于公共领域。
are typically in the public domain.
但如果你从其他来源复制代码，
But if you're copying code from other sources,
它实际上可能是专有的，或者
it may actually be proprietary, or it
可能包含在其他类型的开放源代码许可证中
may be covered by other kinds of open source licenses
这比公共领域更具限制性。
that are more restrictive than the public domain.
记录来源的另一个原因
Another reason for documenting source
代码可能会过时。
is that the code can fall out of date.
所以这段特殊的代码来自堆栈溢出
So this particular bit of code came from a Stack Overflow
关于如何将URL读入字符串的问题。
question about how to read a URL into a string.
所以这实际上有几个答案。
So that actually has several answers.
这是最高评价的答案，
And this is the highest rated answer,
但后来被这个更好的
but was later superseded by this better
在Java库中使用最新API的答案。
answer that uses more recent APIs in the Java library.
所以代码示例可以发展。
So code examples can evolve.
通过记录这个参考，你
And by recording that reference, you
允许维护人员查看
allow the maintainer to go and look and see whether this
仍然是最好的方法。
is still the best way to do it.
所以这些都是好的评论。
So those are good comments.
有些评论是不好的
Some comments are bad, and they're
通常是不好的，因为它们是不必要的。
often bad because they're unnecessary.
所以如果你写的评论只是音译
So if you're writing a comment that simply transliterates
用Java编写成英语的代码，
the code that was written in Java into English,
那就没有任何信息了，
then that doesn't add any information,
它不会使代码更简单
it does nothing to make the code easier
理解或记录假设，
to understand or to document assumptions,
你不应该有这样的评论。
and you should simply not have comments like this.
但如果有不清楚的代码，
But if there is code that's obscure,
很好地说明了代码的实际意图。
it's good to say what the code is actually intended to do.
我们一开始的例子
The example that we had at the beginning
这本书，每年的一天，确实需要一些评论。
this reading, day of year, does need some comments.
它没有任何评论，而且很多评论，
It has no comments at all, and a lot of it,
实际上，很模糊，所以我们在练习中要做一件事
actually, is obscure, so one thing we'll do in the exercises
看看我们可以在代码中添加注释的位置。
is look at where we might put comments into that code.